Guide to the Truman A. Warner Papers MS 026
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
- Series I, Research Files
  - Theater/Movies
    - Regional Theater, New Milford, Conn., 1941-1995 (Box 29, Folder 52)
      Program from Theater-in-the-Dale, 1941. Articles on state theaters.
    - Regional Theater, Ridgefield, Conn., 1930s-1990 (Box 29, Folder 53)
      Articles on Ridgefield Workshop for the Performing Arts. Also, RidgefieldDinner Theater, and Ridgefield Summer Theatre program: The Milky Way, ca 1930s.
    - Regional Theater, Sherman, Conn., 1971-1986 (Box 29, Folder 54)
      Three articles of actors who performed at the Sherman Playhouse.
    - Rogers' Puppets, 1990-1996 (Box 29, Folder 55)
      Two articles about the puppet projects of Robert Rogers of New Milford.56 Southbury Playhouse, Southbury, Conn., 1971-1995 (w/gaps) Articles on the life and times of W. Thomas Littleton's Southbury Playhouse, the demise of the Playhouse by wrecker's ball in 1988, and the demise of Littleton in 1995
    - Starlight Theater, Pawling, New York, 1937-1976 (Box 29, Folder 57)
      Articles outlining the Theater and its owner/producer Isobelle Jones. Three programs: Spooks, and Squaring the Circle, 1938; and You Can't Take It With You, 1939. Theater closed in 1962 after 28 seasons.
  - Topography, Geology, Weather
    Geology - Maps; New England Lime Company; Geology - Connecticut - Moodus; Old New-Gate Prison and Copper Mine - Connecticut; Quadrangle report; no. 7; Old Newgate Prison (East-Granby, Conn.); State Geological and Natural History Survey of Connecticut; Thomas Mountain; Sand and gravel industry - Environmental aspects - Connecticut; Seismology - Connecticut - Moodus; United States. Dept. of the Interior; Tools - United States; Meteorology - Connecticut; Maps; Limekiln Quarry; Minerology - New York (State); Minerology -- Connecticut; Gravel pits; Branchville Quarry; Iron foundries -- Rhode Island; Iron industry; Iron foundries -- Connecticut; Iron foundries -- Massachusetts; Earthquakes; Danbury quadrangle; Farm equipment - New England; Eric Sloane Museum; Connecticut -- Climate; Brookfield Quarry; Copper mines and mining -- Connecticut; Conservation of natural resources -- Connecticut
    - Glaciation, 1937 (Box 29, Folder 71)
      Maps and clippings on Umpog Swamp, Rocky River, and Housatonic River Valley. See also: Still River folder.
    - Thomas Mountain, 1842-1849 (Box 29, Folder 85)
      Research notes, reference to Nichols Diary/Journal, H. Fanton notebook 1848/49. Descriptions of Terre Haute Hotel Danbury and a family coach excursion/picnic up Thomas Mountain circa 1849. See also: Sources, box #1.
    - Geological Times - Animals, Plants, etc., 1904-1968 (Box 29, Folder 70)
      Dinosaur tracks article.
    - Bed Rock - Geology, 1906-1985 (Box 29, Folder 59)
      Clippings, photocopy pages from books, and reference notes from H. Fanton notebook. Student research paper: The Geology of Parts of the Still and Housatonic River Valleys and the Southbury Outlier (a field excursion) by Frederick Bragdon and Donald Groff. 1966. Report: Quadrangle Report No. 7. The Bedrock Geology of the Danbury Quadrangle, with map. 1958.
    - Preliminary Geological Map of Connecticut, 1956 (Folder OS Folder 12)
      Geological and Natural History Survey, Bulletin 84.
    - Topographic Interpretation, undated (Box 29, Folder 87)
      Introduction to maps.
    - Earthquakes, 1698-1985 (Box 29, Folder 67)
      Newspaper articles, Moodus earthquake in 1967, research notes on the eastern seaboard earthquakes, and one page from the Nichols Diary Journal dated 1698-1727.
    - Gravel Pits, 1974-1978 (Box 29, Folder 72)
      Articles on area gravel mining, relocation of burial grounds and cemeteries, Northrop Cemetery, private burial grounds, sand Pit Road, and Simpaug Turnpike.
    - Topography - Physiography - Mountains - Streams, 1867-1977 (Box 29, Folder 88)
      Danbury area topographic survey maps.
    - Lime and Marble, 1975-1983 (Box 29, Folder 75)
      Swim holes, Limekiln Quarry, The New England Lime Company, and Brookfield Quarry.
    - Iron Production, 1728-1982 (Box 29, Folder 74)
      Articles and notes on iron in the Revolution, Salisbury and Kent blast furnaces, local iron furnaces, welding, ironworkers, Bull's Bridge Forge. Pamphlet on New-Gate Prison and Copper Mine. Research paper: Untitled and author Fred ? (no last name).
    - Mines & Mining - Minerals, 1859-1984 (Box 29, Folder 76)
      Articles and research notes on early mining in Danbury and mineralogy, O. P. Clark, Danbury Gold Mine 1881, Danburite Charles A. Shepherd 1939, North Street, Pandanaram Road, Merryall Mine, MAG Mining Co., Tilly Foster Mine, and local mineralogists Ronald Januzzi, John A. Pawlowski, and Howard J. Hewett.
    - Roxbury - Iron Hill, 1964-1983 (Box 29, Folder 78)
      Clippings, maps, and research notes on DEP Furnace Restoration Project 1974, Land Trust Bulletin, and report by the Roxbury Land Trust on the Mine Hill Preserve.
    - Tilly Foster - Putnam County - Iron Mines, 1964-1981 (Box 29, Folder 86)
      History of Tilly Foster Iron Mine, and reference to Ronald E. Januzzi.
    - Soil and Farm Usage, 1634-1977 (Box 29, Folder 79)
      Research notes on early farm settlements 1630-1650, Conn. agricultural history, farm inventories, soil surveys, land use, and farm appraisals. See also: Farming
    - Soils, 1821-1979 (Box 29, Folder 80)
      Research notes on soil conservation, and land resources. See also: Farming.
    - Fairfield County, Connecticut; Advance Soil Survey Maps, 1977-1979 (Box OS 1, Folder *)
      March 1977: 8 maps; January 1978: 2 maps; March 1978: 2 maps; June 1979: 1 map.
    - Erosion Control, 1967-1979 (Box 29, Folder 69)
      Clippings on soil erosion, soil sloping, and soil conservation in the Still River Valley; 1977 Route 7 Expressway construction, topography, sediment control, and rezoning issues (Brookfield). Booklet: Erosion and Sediment Control Handbook; Connecticut by the U.S. Department of Agriculture, Storrs, Conn., 1976; and, Regional Planning Bulletin No. 7, "Erosion & Sediment Source Inventory" May 1979.
    - Climatic Zones, 1965-1989 (Box 29, Folder 64-65)
      Articles on global weather conditions and their effect on New England in the present century. Research notes and general synopsis of weather conditions in Connecticut from 1683.
    - Cooling Trends and Little Ice Age, 1934-1982 (Box 29, Folder 66)
      Research notes and articles on changing weather patterns.
    - Summer of 1816 & Other Cold Periods, 1815-1996 (Box 29, Folder 83)
      Research notes and articles.
    - Storm/Lightning, 1942-1982 (Box 29, Folder 82)
    - Spring, 1837-1984 (Box 29, Folder 81)
      Nichols Diary, poems, and newspaper articles.
    - Summer of 1816 and other cold periods, 1815-1996 (Box 29, Folder 83)
    - Summer, 1848-1849 (Box 29, Folder 84)
      Nichols Diary and reference to 1848 earthquake.
    - Autumn, 1968-1977 (Box 29, Folder 58)
      Articles and diary notation of First Frost of the Season.
    - Blizzard of 1934, 1934-1977 (Box 29, Folder 62)
      Articles regarding 1934 blizzard.
    - Blizzard of 1888, 1938-1988 (Box 29, Folder 61)
    - Blizzard of 1978 (Box 29, Folder 63)
    - Tornados, 1949-1989 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Winter Climate, 1690-1996 (Box 30, Folder 2-3)
      articles.Articles and research notes on weather conditions/events, hurricanes, local tornadoes, and weather patterns. Dr. Melvin Goldstein featured in many
    - Winter Weather, 1780-1985 (Box 30, Folder 4)
      Research notes, Nichols diary, and newspaper articles.
    - Winter 1995-1996 (Box 30, Folder 5)
      Newspaper articles and editorials.
  - Transportation, EarlyRoads, Highways, Autos and Trucks
    Transportation-Connecticut-DanburyRegion; Trolley cars; Inland water transportation-Connecticut; Covered bridges-Connecticut; Farmington Canal; Historic bridges -- Connecticut; Connecticut.Dept.ofTransportation; Connecticut -- History; Connecticut -- Roads; Bridges-Connecticut; Bridges -- Connecticut -- Maintenance and repair; Bus lines -- Connecticut -- Danbury Region; Canals-Connecticut; Redding (Conn.) -- History
    - Automobiles - Early, 1907-1995 (Box 30, Folder 6)
      Articles and notes on the first forty years of the DMV, Danbury antique car shows, and auto racing at the Fairgrounds. See also: Danbury Fair and Circus.
    - Automobiles/Taxis, 1960-1996 (Box 30, Folder 7)
      Articles and research notes on van pools, advent of the small car, airport limousine service, and the new Danbury DMV 1972. Student report by Steve Pichiarallo for Modern Complex Society (no title/date).
    - Bicycles/Motorcycles, 1902-1995 (Box 30, Folder 8)
      Research notes and articles on Still River bicycle trail, Linear Park, and Marcus Dairy tradition.
    - Bridges, 1768-1996 (Box 30, Folder 9)
      Research notes and articles on area historic bridges and their preservation. 10-11 Bus/Taxi/Limousine, 1931-1996 (w/gaps) Research notes and articles on bus routes, timetables, Hart, Greyhound, and Bonanza.
    - Canals, 1820-1987 (Box 30, Folder 12)
      Research notes and articles on the Housatonic Canal 1827, nineteenth century canals, environmental battles, 60 locks on Farmington Canal 1828-1847, Danbury/Westport Canal 1820. Booklet: Boats Across New England Hills; The Story of the Farmington Canal, 1941.
    - Commuting, 1965-1995 (Box 30, Folder 13-16)
      Articles on growth and change in Fairfield County, commuters problems, and need for new highways. Reports by the Housatonic Valley Council of Elected Officials, Commuter Travel Patterns, 1994; and, Transportation Plan for the Housatonic Valley Region, Draft Edition, April 1977.
    - Gas Stations/Repairs/Garages, 1972-1985 (Box 30, Folder 17)
      Research on old area gas stations, now defunct, and New England traditions and old time service.
    - Horse Drawn Vehicles/Livery, 1796-1986 (Box 30, Folder 18)
      Articles and research notes on post roads/carriages, Bill Jackson, livery man in Danbury, and Danbury stage coach.
    - Roads (Early) & Highways, 1777-1978 (Box 30, Folder 19-20)
      Research notes and articles on colonial roads, post roads, and milestones and early road making. Student paper: Contour Analysis Project by Jim Saghir.
    - Roads & Highways, 1968-1995 (Box 30, Folder 21)
      Roads and Highways, 1968-1995 (w/gaps)Research notes, articles and maps on roadways around Danbury. Student paper: Roadways Around Danbury by Bryan Lambert.22 Roads, Travel, Maps, Revolution, 1730-1977 (w/gaps) Articles and research notes on early travel routes, ferries, and roads. See also Student Research Papers #67: Roads and Highways in the Danbury Area During the Revolution Era by William J. Clark. See also: American Revolution
    - Transportation Problems, 1647-1994 (Box 30, Folder 23)
      Research notes and articles on turnpikes, old roads, need for better mass transportation system, area growth, CT Bureau of Highways and CT Public Expenditure Council. See also: Highways
    - Trolley Cars, 1964-1996 (Box 30, Folder 24)
      Articles on Scott Fanton Museum trolley artifacts, and City Center Trolley.
    - Trucks, 1970-1994 (Box 30, Folder 25-26)
      Articles on weigh stations, violations, tolls, highway damage, manifests, tandems, and truck stops.
    - Turnpikes, 1795-1986 (Box 30, Folder 27-28)
      Articles and research notes on the turnpikes of Connecticut.
  - Western Connecticut State University
    - History
      - Administration, 1965-1997 (Box 30, Folder 29-31a)
        Bersi, Braun, Buccini, Cook, Dennis, Dozier, Drobish, Feldman, Hawkes, Kalogeras, Kinney, Leuthauser, Muska, Nichols, LaFond, Lemoine, O'Neill, Pegolotti, Trimpert, Pettersch, Puffett, Raglan, Rudner, Steinkrauss, Teal, Roach, Terry, Theisen, Wagner, Watjen, and Wilds (see Terry).
      - Alumni Association, undated (Box 30, Folder 32)
        List of alumnae (no date) and miscellaneous notices. Alumni newsletters removed and filed in Record Group 5: Alumni Affairs.
      - AAUP - Ad Hoc Committee on Faculty Morale, 1989-1990 (Box 30, Folder 33-35)
        Correspondence, surveys, and a copy of A History of Western Connecticut State University, 1978-1993 by Edwin A. Rosenberg. See also: Record Group 3: Governance
      - Anthropology 400s, 1969-1973 (Box 30, Folder 36)
        Correspondence and Social Science/History Departmental Handbook, 1969-1970.
      - Anthropology-Sociology Majors, 1974 (Box 30, Folder 37)
        Course requirements for proposed Sociology-Anthropology majors.
      - Arts Festival, 1966-1982 (Box 30, Folder 38)
        DSC's Music Department and SGA co-sponsored the first annual Arts Festival. Newspaper clippings and programs on various performances.
      - Basic Studies, 1973-1990 (Box 30, Folder 39)
        Clippings discuss revamping program.
      - Center for Urban Studies, 1981-1983 (Box 30, Folder 40-42)
        Correspondence pertaining to the Center for Urban Studies at WCSU. See also: Herbert F. Janick, Jr. Papers.
      - College Foundation-Wesconn, 1971-1989 (Box 30, Folder 43)
        Copies of By-Laws, Certificate of Incorporation, Trust Agreement, Financial Statement (1987) Freedom of Information and The University Foundation of Western Connecticut, Inc. by Barbara Obeda (1987), and clippings.
      - Commencement Programs, 1970-1995 (Box 30, Folder 44-47)
        Includes Honors Assembly (1971), and inauguration program of F. Burton Cook as fourth president of Post Junior College (1971), and 1995 Commencement Address. See also: Record Group 4: University Events.
      - Community Action - Levy, 1967-1973 (Box 30, Folder 48-59)
        Correspondence, clippings, and reports regarding community needs and WCSC's Community Action Program.
      - Connecticut - Commission of Higher Education, 1970-1972 (Box 30, Folder 60-63)
        Correspondence regarding Master Plan Development for the state system of higher education, Annual Enrollment Survey (1970-71), and Colloquium on Higher Education in Connecticut (1972). Autograph letter to Warner from Thomas J. Meskill, Governor of Connecticut, dated September 21, 1972.
      - Curriculum Analysis Committee, 1970-1972 (Box 31, Folder 1)
        Correspondence on suggested and projected programs in anthropology, and Curriculum Committee minutes. See also: Record Group 3: Governance.
      - Curriculum Issues, 1966-1976 (Box 31, Folder 1-6)
        Correspondence, minutes of Curriculum Committee meetings, and course outlines. See also: Record Group 3: Governance.
      - Department Meetings, 1969-1975 (Box 31, Folder 7-8)
        Correspondence regarding curriculum changes and requirements. See also: Record Group 3: Governance.
      - Department Notices, 1970-1994 (Box 31, Folder 9)
        Correspondence concerning the Social Science Department.
      - Diversity and Multicultural Plan, 1990-1993 (Box 31, Folder 10)
        Plan to promote pluralism and evaluation report. See also: Record Group 2: Office of the President.
      - Ethics Committee, 1980-1983 (Box 31, Folder 11-15)
        Correspondence concerns a study of ethical practices at WCSU.
      - Faculty Handbooks, 1956 (Box 31, Folder 16)
      - Faculty Handbook, 1966 (Box 31, Folder 17)
      - Faculty Handbook, 1968 (Box 31, Folder 18-19)
      - Faculty Handbook, 1969 (Box 31, Folder 20-23)
      - Faculty Handbook, 1973 (Box 31, Folder 24-26)
      - Faculty Handbook, 1973 (Box 31, Folder 27-28)
      - Faculty Senate - Ad Hoc Committee, 1974 (Box 31, Folder 29)
        Minutes of the Promotions and Tenure Committee.
      - Faculty Senate - Ad Hoc Committee, 1974-1975 (Box 31, Folder 30-31)
      - Faculty Senate - C2 Committee (The Committee on Committees), 1975-1977 (Box 31, Folder 32-33)
        Correspondence, procedures for tenure and promotion, and information on committee structure and recommendations for change.
      - Faculty Senate, 1968-1977 (Box 31, Folder 34-38)
        Correspondence, Constitution of the Faculty Senate, C2 Committee Reports and personnel policies from the State of Connecticut, Board of Trustees.
      - Faculty Senate/Geology Program, 1990 (Box 31, Folder 39)
        Discontinuance of geology program.
    - WCSU Faculty, 1963-1997
      - A, undated (Box 31, Folder 40)
      - B, undated (Box 31, Folder 41)
      - C, undated (Box 31, Folder 42)
      - D, undated (Box 31, Folder 43)
      - E, undated (Box 31, Folder 44)
      - F, undated (Box 31, Folder 45)
      - G, undated (Box 31, Folder 46)
      - H-I, undated (Box 31, Folder 47)
      - J-K, undated (Box 31, Folder 48)
      - L, undated (Box 31, Folder 49)
      - M, undated (Box 31, Folder 50)
      - N-Q, undated (Box 31, Folder 51)
      - R, undated (Box 31, Folder 52)
      - S, undated (Box 31, Folder 53)
      - T, undated (Box 31, Folder 54)
      - W-Y, undated (Box 31, Folder 55)
      - Graduate Courses & Program, 1960-1968 (Box 31, Folder 56)
        Requirements for graduate degree in history.
      - History - M A. Program, 1970-1971 (Box 31, Folder 57)
        Information on proposed courses for Master of Arts Program in history.
      - History/Soc. Science Dept. Minutes, etc., 1962-1976 (Box 31, Folder 58-60)
        Minutes of meetings.
      - Library, 1966-1994 (Box 31, Folder 61)
        Clippings regarding construction of a new library and naming it in honor of Ruth Haas, lack of resources, donations of books, staff and money issues, and monetary gift to establish the Robert S. Young Memorial Library.
      - Library Policy Committee, 1973-1978 (Box 31, Folder 62-64)
        Correspondence, minutes of meetings, 1974-75 Report of the Director, 1976- 1977 and 1977-1978 Budget Proposals, policies and procedures.
      - Long Range Planning, undated-1988 (Box 32, Folder 1)
        Correspondence regarding School of Arts & Sciences courses.
      - NCATE, 1968 (Box 32, Folder 2)
        Reappraisal Report to the National Council for the Accreditation of Teacher Education, October 1968.
      - New Campus - Anthropology, 1974 (Box 32, Folder 3)
        Sketch of Anthropology Lab and equipment needed for new campus.
      - Non-Western Culture Issue, 1989 (Box 32, Folder 4)
        Correspondence regarding definition of term "Non-Western" culture.
      - Social Science Department, 1986-1995 (Box 32, Folder 5-8)
        Correspondence, clippings, enrollment statistics, Department Bylaws, annual reports, and minutes of meetings.
      - Social Science "Mission", 1969 (Box 32, Folder 9)
        Correspondence regarding developing Mission Statement.
      - Social Science - M.S., undated (Box 32, Folder 10)
        Approved courses for M.S. degree in Education.
      - Sociology - M. A. Program, 1970-1971 (Box 32, Folder 11)
        Information on Master of Arts Program in sociology, and demands of Afro- American students for black studies program.
      - Sports, 1970-1996 (Box 32, Folder 12-15)
        Newspaper coverage of sports at WCSU. Student Papers - History of DSC, 1962-1966 (w/gaps)
      - Asselta, Richard: An Anthropological Observation of the Danbury State College Community. (May, 1966)., undated (Box 32, Folder 16)
      - Bard, Elizabeth: A Sociological Examination of a College Student HONOR COURT. (Nov. 12, 1962). (Box 32, Folder 17)
      - Bick, Michael A.: Power Structure of Administration and Student, undated (Box 32, Folder 18)
        Body. (May 27, 1966)
      - Contois, William: An Analysis of Danbury State College as an, undated (Box 32, Folder 19)
        Institution. (May 27, 1966).
      - Master, Robert J.: Report on Fairfield Hall. (Jan. 16, 1965)., undated (Box 32, Folder 20)
      - Mattiello, Arthur: Kitchen, Memorial Hall. (Jan. 2, 1962)., undated (Box 32, Folder 21)
      - Millea, Thomas: Danbury State College - Institutional Analysis. n.d., undated (Box 32, Folder 22)
      - Schipul, Robert: Notes on a College Campus-Danbury State. (May 27, 1966); and,Schipul, Robert: Notes on a College Campus-Danbury State. (May 30, 1966) (Box 32, Folder 23)
      - Trudel, Romuald Jr.: The Role of Religion on the Danbury, undated (Box 32, Folder 24)
        State College Campus. (An Independent Research Study). (May 31, 1965).
      - Students - Unique Stories, 1965-1996 (Box 32, Folder 25-26)
      - SGA Evaluation, 1969-1970 (Box 32, Folder 27)
        The Evaluation of Faculty, Fall Semester, 1969, Western Connecticut State College. Presented by the 1969-1970 Student Government Association.
      - Teachers Ed Program (Revision), 1970 (Box 32, Folder 28)
        Correspondence with regard to keeping pace with current needs of secondary school student teachers.
      - Theater, 1974-1994 (Box 32, Folder 29)
        Programs and clippings regarding stage productions at WCSU.
      - Union Issues and State Funding, 1970-1980 (Box 32, Folder 30)
        Newsletters and flyers regarding issues and funding. See also: Record Group 3, Governance, for additional information.
      - University Activities, 1985-1988 (Box 32, Folder 31)
        Faculty in Focus (1985), and Some Ruminations on the Challenges before the Faculty Today by Jim Pegolotti (1985).
      - WestConn Administrative Correspondence, 1977-1994 (Box 32, Folder 32)
        Memos regarding University policies and procedures. This file is not a comprehensive collection of campus policies. See also: WCSU Archival Collections, Record Group 3, Governance, for additional information.
    - WCSU - Chronology, faculty, and students.
      Newspaper clippings covering campus growth and expansion,
      - 1907 & 1940s (Box 32, Folder 33-34)
      - 1950s (Box 32, Folder 35)
      - 1960-1963 (Box 32, Folder 36)
      - 1964-1965 (Box 32, Folder 37)
      - 1966 (Box 32, Folder 38)
      - 1967 (Box 32, Folder 39)
      - 1968 (Box 32, Folder 40)
      - 1969 (Box 32, Folder 41)
      - 1970 (Box 32, Folder 42)
      - 1971 (Box 32, Folder 43)
      - 1972 (Box 32, Folder 44)
      - 1973 (Box 32, Folder 45)
      - 1974 (Box 32, Folder 46)
      - 1975 (Box 32, Folder 47-48)
      - 1976 (Box 32, Folder 49)
      - 1977 (Box 32, Folder 50-51)
      - 1978 (Box 32, Folder 52)
      - 1979 (Box 32, Folder 53-55)
      - 1980 (Box 32, Folder 56)
      - 1981 (Box 32, Folder 57)
      - 1982 (Box 32, Folder 58)
      - 1983 (Box 32, Folder 59-60)
      - 1984 (Box 32, Folder 61)
      - 1985 (Box 32, Folder 62)
      - 1986 (Box 32, Folder 63)
      - 1987 (Box 32, Folder 64)
      - 1988 (Box 32, Folder 65)
      - 1989 (Box 32, Folder 66)
      - 1990 (Box 32, Folder 67)
      - 1991 (Box 32, Folder 68)
      - 1992 (Box 32, Folder 69)
      - 1993 (Box 32, Folder 70)
      - 1994 (Box 32, Folder 71)
      - 1995 (Box 32, Folder 72)
      - 1996 (Box 32, Folder 73)
      - 1997 (Box 32, Folder 74)
- Series II: Manuscript
  There is no indication of chapter numbers for the records after chaper 5 (Post Revolution to Civil War).
  Mercury -- Toxicology; Manors - New York (State) - History; New York (State) - History - Colonial period, ca. 1600-1775; Landlord and tenant - New York (State) - History; Land tenure -- New York (State); Land grants -- New York (State); Language and culture - United States; Labor unions -- United States; Labor laws and legislation - United States; English language - United States - History; Freemasonry - New England - History - 19th century; African Americans -- Languages; Danbury (Conn.) -- History.; Connecticut -- History -- 17th century -- Sources; African Americans; Connecticut -- History -- 18th century -- Sources; United States - History - Colonial period, ca. 1600-1775; United Mine Workers of America; Underground railroad - Connecticut; Banks and banking -- United States -- Connecticut.
  - Chapter 1
    - Indians, undated (Box 37, Folder 1)